A Finding Aid to the Eva Lee Gallery Records, 1921-1973, in the Archives of American Art AAA.evalee
Archives of American Art
Eva Lee Gallery records
1921-1973
AAA.evalee
Archives of American Art
4 Linear feet
The scattered records of the New York contemporary American art Eva Lee Gallery measure 4.0 linear feet and date from 1921-1973. Artist files contain provenance notes, photographs of artwork, records of sales and consignments, exhibition catalogs from other galleries, and reference information on numerous contemporary artists, many represented by the gallery. There are also scattered letters and artwork from artists, scattered sales records of J.B. Neuman's New Art Circle Gallery, and a photocopy of an auction catalog for Korvettes Art Galleries in Douglastan, New York. A significant amount of information is found within the collection about Alexander Calder, Lovis Corinth, Salvadore Dali, Lyonel Feininger, George Grosz, Robert Indiana, Harry Lieberman, Rene Magritte, John Marin, Lowell Nesbitt, Ben Shahn, Victor Vasarely, and Max Weber.
Eva Lee Gallery
Provenance
The Eva Lee Gallery records were donated in 1973 by Eva Lee through Eloise Spaeth, and in 1978 by Neal Richmond of the Paul Klapper Library, Queens College, Flushing, New York, who had been asked to disperse Lee's gallery records following her sudden death in 1973. A photocopy of the Korvettes Art Galleries Auction Catalog was donated by Eva Lee in 1970.
Lee's records also contained financial files belonging to art dealer J. B. Neumann and his New Art Circle Gallery, whose estate she had worked on in 1966.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection was digitized in 2015 and is available on the Archives of American Art's website. Materials which have not been scanned include blank pages, blank versos of photographs, and duplicates. In some cases, exhibition catalogs and other publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Historical Note
Eva Lee was born circa 1924. She fled from Nazi Germany to the United States, becoming an art dealer and the owner of the Eva Lee Gallery, Inc. Located in Great Neck, New York, the Eva Lee Gallery specialized in modern art and handled the work of many prominent artists including Alexander Calder, Lyonel Feininger, George Grosz, Marsden Hartley, Jacob Lawrence, Ben Shahn, and Max Weber. The gallery was in operation through the first half of 1973.
Eva Lee died suddenly on November 4, 1973 in Terre Haute, Indiana, while undergoing unspecified medical treatment.
Scope and Content Note
The scattered records of the New York contemporary American art Eva Lee Gallery measure 4.0 linear feet and date from 1921-1973. Artist files contain provenance notes, photographs of artwork, records of sales and consignments, exhibition catalogs from other galleries, and reference information on numerous contemporary artists, many represented by the gallery. There are also scattered letters and artwork from artists, scattered sales records of J.B. Neumann's New Art Circle Gallery, and a photocopy of an auction catalog for Korvettes Art Galleries in Douglastan, New York.
The records are comprised of artists' files arranged into four categories established by the gallery: general artists' files; notebooks of artists' files; financial artists' files; and consignment and sales artists' files. General artists' files contain background and reference information on numerous contemporary artists, performers, and art-related organizations. More information exists for Alexander Calder and Harry Lieberman than the other names represented in the general files. Lee also arranged provenance notes and photographs of artwork into notebooks, presumably including many of the artists represented by the gallery. There is a significant amount of material in the notebooks on Alexander Calder, Robert Indiana, Lowell Nesbitt, Ben Shahn, Victor Vasarely, and Max Weber.
Financial artists' files contain correspondence with artists and patrons concerning the sale of artwork by both the Eva Lee Gallery and J. B. Neumann of the New Art Circle Gallery, scattered artwork, printed material, photographs of artists, and checks signed by Neumann and endorsed by miscellaneous artists. Eva Lee worked on the estate of J. B. Neumann and collected and interspersed his files with her own. These files include letters from Josef Albers, Thomas Hart Benton, Alexander Calder, Christo, Joseph Cornell, Robert Indiana, and a postcard of Calder's studio from Ben Shahn. There are also watercolor sketches by Clifford Odets, an exhibition catalog autographed by Ben Shahn, and photographs of Marsden Hartley, Jacques Lipchitz, composer Frederick Loewe, Paul Mommer, Mert Simpson, and Curt Valentin with Andrew Ritchie.
Eva Lee Gallery artists' consignment and sales files primarily contain photographs of artwork and notes concerning sales of specific artwork by the Eva Lee Gallery. Also found in these sales files are scattered letters, receipts, and printed material. There is a significant amount of material for Ben Benn, Alexander Calder, Lovis Corinth, Salvadore Dali, Lyonel Feininger, George Grosz, Marsden Hartley, John Hopkins, Rene Magritte, and John Marin. It is assumed that Eva Lee separated the two latter sets of artists' files containing sales records.
Also found in the collection is a photocopy of the Korvettes Art Galleries auction catalog, which lists artwork sold at a 1970 auction liquidating the holdings of the Douglaston, New York gallery.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: General Artist Files, 1923-1972 (Boxes 1-2; 1.3 linear feet)
Series 2: Notebooks of Artist Files, 1929-1973 (Boxes 2-3; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 3: Financial Artist Files, 1921-1970 (Boxes 3-4; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 4: Eva Lee Gallery Consignment and Sales Artist Files, 1960-1972 (Box 4; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 5: Photocopy of Korvettes Art Galleries Auction Catalog, 1970 (Box 4; 1 folder)
Albers, Josef; Benn, Ben, 1884-; Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Christo, 1935-; Corinth, Lovis, 1858-1925; Cornell, Joseph; Dalí, Salvador, 1904-; Feininger, Lyonel, 1871-1956; Grosz, George, 1893-1959; Hartley, Marsden, 1877-1943; Hopkins, John; Indiana, Robert, 1928-; Korvettes; Lee, Eva; Lieberman, Harry, 1880-1983; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Loewe, Frederick; Magritte, René, 1898-1967; Marin, John, 1870-1953; Mommer, Paul; Nesbitt, Lowell, 1933-1993; Neumann, J. B. (Jsrael Ber); New Art Circle (New York, N.Y.); Odets, Clifford, 1906-1963; Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff; Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969; Simpson, Merton D. (Merton Daniel), 1928-; Valentin, Curt, 1902-1954; Vasarely, Victor, 1906-1997; Weber, Max, 1881-1961; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--Long Island; Photographs; Watercolor drawings; Works of art
- General Artist Files, 1923-1972; Series 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists primarily of reference files containing brief biographical accounts, clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, miscellaneous printed material, and scattered photographs of artwork for numerous contemporary artists - presumbably some, but not all, represented by the gallery. Performers and a few art-related organizations are represented in the files. A few of the files also contain scattered letters and receipts. More information is found for Alexander Calder and Harry Lieberman than for the other artists, and there are photographs of Harold Altman, Harry Lieberman, and Paul Mommer. There is also an exhibition catalog autographed by Luigi Corbellini.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by surname of the artist.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. In some cases exhibition catalogs and other publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
  - Adler, Jankel, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Altman, Harold, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amen, Irving, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Antreasian, Garo Z., circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anuszkiewicz, Richard, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arman, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aronson, Boris, 1941-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aronson, David, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arp, Jean, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Associated American Artists, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bargheer, Eduard, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Barooshian, Martin, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Barr, Norman, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baskin, Leonard, 1956-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bayer, Herbert, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baylinson, A. S., 1938-1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Beck, Margit, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Becker, Maurice, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Becket, Marta (mime dancer), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Beckmann, Max, 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Benn, Ben, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Benno, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Benton, Fletcher, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Berlin, Beatrice Winn, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bernhard, Georg, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Berrocal, Miguel, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bertoia, Harry, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Biddle, George, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Biel-Bienne, Eugene V., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bill, Jakob, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Blatas, Arbit, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bloch, Albert, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bluemner, Oscar, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Blumberg, Yuli, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Borgenicht, Grace (art dealer), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Boto, Martha, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brady, Mei, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Brandt, Warren, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Brody, Iris, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Browne, Byron, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Buffet, Bernard, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Buffet, Maurice, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Burba, Tadas, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Burch, Claire, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Burkhard, Henri, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Burlin, Paul, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Burliuk, David, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Buzzelli, J. Anthony, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Caesar, Davis, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Calcagno, Lawrence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 52-53)
  - Canevari, Angelo, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Caparn, Rhys, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Cariola, Robert, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Caro, Anthony, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Castellon, Frederico, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Castro-Cid, Enrique, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Charlot, Jean, 1931-1945 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Chambers, John, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Cherney, Marvin, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Chirino, Martin, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Christo, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Chumley, John, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Claisse, Genevieve, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Clawson, Rex, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Constant, George, 1929-1966 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Corbellini, Luigi, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Corbino, Jon, 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Corinth, Lovis, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Corita, Sister Mary, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Cruikshank, George, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cuevas, José Luis, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cugat, Xavier, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Cummings, Willard W., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Cusumano, Stefano, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Delauney (Terk), Sonia, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - del Prado, Marina Nuñez, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Demarco, Hugo, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Gemini Graphic Editions, Ltd., circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Herbin, Auguste, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - King, Tony, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Kollwitz, Käthe, 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Krauskopf, Bruno, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Kupferman, Lawrence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Kurzweil, Max, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Lachaise, Gaston, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Lambert, Georges, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Landau, Jacob, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Lang, David, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Laske, Oskar, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Lawrence, Jacob, 1942-1968 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Lee, Doris, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Le Parc, Julio, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Levine, David, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Levinson, Mon, 1961-1972 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Lieberman, Harry, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    Biographical materials, correspondence.
  - Lieberman, Harry, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 102-105)
    Notebooks.
  - Lieberman, Harry, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 106-109)
    Printed material.
  - Litwak, Israel (Ray), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Lomoff, Joseph, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Louis, Morris, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Lurig, Boris, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Luther, A. (Adolf), circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Lutz, Dan, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Lytle, Richard, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Mack, Heinz, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Macris, Constantin, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Magritte, Rene, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Maillol, Aristide, circa 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Marca-Relli, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Margoulies, Berta, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Margulies, Joseph, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Marin, John, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Marisol (Escobar), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marsh, Reginald, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Masereel, Frans, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Masson, Andre, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menkes, Zygmunt (Sigmund), circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Michelson, Leo, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Micus, Eduard, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miro, Joan, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mommer, Paul, 1951-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mondrian, Piet, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Morellet, François, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mortensen, Richard, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mosca, August, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Moses, Grandma, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Naito, Rakuko, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nesbitt, Lowell, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Okimoto, Jerry Tsukio, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Parker, Robert Andrew, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pascal, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Peirce, Waldo, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Penny, James, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Perutz, Dolly, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Peterdi, Gabor, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Peterson, Roland, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Philipp, Robert, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Philipp, Walter, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Picabia, Francis, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pillin, Polia, 1955-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Pippin, Horace, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Pirandello, Fausto, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Pollock, Jackson, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Porter, David, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Porzano, Giacomo, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Posada, Jose Guadalupe, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Post, Charles, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Powers, Frances, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Prampolini, Enrico, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Preston, Malcolm, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Schöffer, Nicolas, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Sobrino, Francisco, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Sonderborg, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Soto, Jesus-Rafael, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Stein, Joel, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Tomasello, Luis, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Vasarely, Victor, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Weinberg, Elbert, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Yvaral, Jean Pierre, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Notebooks of Artist Files, 1929-1973; Series 2
  The contents of these loose-leaf notebooks include scattered letters, provenance notes concerning sales of artwork, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs of artwork. There is a significant amount of material in the notebooks on Alexander Calder, Robert Indiana, Lowell Nesbitt, Ben Shahn, Victor Vasarely, and Max Weber. There is a letter of authentication signed by Victor Vasarely, a reproduction of a photograph autographed by Salvadore Dali, and a catalog from the first exhibition of mobiles by Alexander Calder at the Buchholz Gallery.
  Notebooks generally contain files arranged alphabetically by artist name but some variations should be noted: see Notebook 16 for "Pop Artists" and Notebook 24 for additional A-Z files.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Notebook 1 (Box 2)
    - Josef Albers, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Ivan Albright, Americana, circa 1930-1965 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Richard Anuszkiewicz, David Aronson, Jean Arp, Milton Avery, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Notebook 2 (Box 2)
    - Leonard Baskin, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Herbert Bayer, Ben Benn, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Thomas Hart Benton, Ben-Zion, Eugene Berman, Floriano Bodini, Camille Bombois, Grace Borgenicht, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Louis Bosa, Iris Brody, Bernard Buffet, Burchfield, David Burliuk, 1939-1973 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Notebook 3 (Box 2)
    - Nino Caffe, Marc Chagall, Christo, George Constant, Jon Corbino, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Lovis Corinth, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Notebook 4: Alexander Calder, 1949-1973 (Box 2, Folder 59-62)
  - Notebook 5: Alexander Calder, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 63-67)
  - Notebook 6 (Box 2)
    - Salvadore Dali, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Willem De Kooning, Elsie Driggs, Jean Dubuffet, Jean Dufy, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Notebook 7: Louis Eilshemius, Max Ernst, Philip Evergood, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Notebook 8: Lyonel Feininger, Sue Fuller, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Notebook 9 (Box 2)
    - W. Gaul, Albert Gleizes, William Gropper, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - George Grosz, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Jean Baptiste Armand Guillaumin, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Notebook 10 (Box 2)
    - Marsden Hartley, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 75-77)
    - Eric Heckel, Barbara Hepworth, Auguste Herbin, Anton Heyboer, Clinton Hill, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Carl Hofer, John Hopkins, Isabella Howland, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Notebook 11: Robert Indiana, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Notebook 12 (Box 2)
    - Morris Kantor, Barnard Karfiol, Ellsworth Kelly, Paul Klee, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Käthe Kollwitz, Benjamin Kopman, Karl Heinz Krause, Nicholas Krushenick, Walt Kuhn, Robert Kulicke, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Notebook 13 (Box 2)
    - Wilfredo Lam, Marie Laurencin, Jacob Lawrence, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Lawrence Lebduska, Jack Levine, Mon Levinson, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Notebook 14 (Box 2)
    - Rene Magritte, László Maholy-Nagy, Artistide Maillol, Giacomo Manzu, 1929-1972 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - John Marin, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Marino Marini, Marisol (Escobar), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Reginald Marsh, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Henri Matisse, Zygmunt Menkes, Paul Mommer, Richard Mortensen, Fernand Mourlot, Otto Mueller, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Notebook 15: Lowell Nesbitt, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Notebook 16 (Box 2)
    - Lynfield Ott, Jules Pascin, Eleven Pop Artists including Allan D'Archangelo, Jim Dine, Allen Jones, Gerald Laing, Roy Lichtenstein, Peter Phillips, Mel Ramos, James Rosenquist, Andy Warhol, John Wesley, Tom Wesselmann, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Pablo Picasso, 1959-1973 (Box 2, Folder 93-94)
  - Notebook 17 (Box 3)
    - Odilon Redon, George Rickey, Boardman Robinson, Auguste Rodin, Umberto Romano, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Egon Schiele, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Kurt Seligman, Charles Sheeler, Moses Soyer, Raphael Soyer, Carol Summers, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 18: Ben Shahn, 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Notebook 19: Ben Shahn, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7-11)
  - Notebook 20: Dorothea Tanning, Mark Tobey, Ernest Trova, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 21 (Box 3)
    - Maurice Utrillo, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Victor Vasarely, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
    - Marcel Vertes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Notebook 22, 1965-1970 (Box 3)
    - Max Weber, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18-21)
      Oils, drawings, graphics.
    - Max Weber, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22-28)
      Notebook.
  - Notebook 23 (Box 3)
    - Andy Warhol, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
    - William Zorach, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Notebook 24 (Box 3)
    - Jean Arp, Milton Avery, Ben Benn, David Burliuk, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Alexander Calder, Jon Corbino, Salvadore Dali, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Dietz Edzard, Philip Evergood, George Grosz, Marsden Hartley, circa 1930-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Robert Indiana, Jacob Lawrence, Roy Lichtenstein, Marisol (Escobar), 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Pablo Picasso, Pre-Columbian Sculpture, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Ben Shahn, Moses Soyer, Andy Warhol, Max Weber, Andrew Wyeth, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Financial Artist Files, 1921-1970; Series 3
  This series contains correspondence with artists and patrons concerning sales of artwork by Eva Lee and J. B. Neumann of the New Art Circle Gallery. It includes letters from Josef Albers, Thomas Hart Benton, Alexander Calder, Christo, Joseph Cornell, Robert Indiana, and a postcard of Calder's studio from Ben Shahn. Also found here are checks signed by Neumann and endorsed by miscellaneous artists, scattered artwork including watercolor sketches by Clifford Odets, miscellaneous printed material including an exhibition catalog autographed by Ben Shahn, and photographs of Marsden Hartley, Jacques Lipchitz, composer Frederick Loewe, Paul Mommer, Mert Simpson, and Curt Valentin with Andrew Ritchie.
  - Abrams, Lillian, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Albers, Josef, 1934-1969 (Box 3, Folder 39-44)
  - Alsterlund, Henrietta, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Altman, Harold, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Armitage, Merle, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Aronson, Boris, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Ault, George, 1926-1945 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Barnes Foundation, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Barr, Alfred, Jr., 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Beck, Margit, circa 1930-1965 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Becker, Maurice, 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Benn, Ben, 1928-1936 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ben-Zion, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Biddle, George, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Bluemner, Oscar, 1924-1941 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Blumberg, Fega, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Brook, Alexander, 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Burkhard, Henri, 1929-1932 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Burkhardt, Robert, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Burliuk, David, 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Callery, Mary, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Christo, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Collingwood, Charles, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Constant, George, 1924-1966 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Corbino, Jon, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Cornell, Joseph, 1946-1964 (Box 3, Folder 73)